Guide to the Engin Ozendes Collection of Ottoman photography AD.MC.012
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Engin Ozendes Collection
1900-1920
1890-1920
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
G. Glikeas (Glykias), Phener Rue Balat, Sokak Apti Sou-Bashi no. 15, Constantinople (Fener, Fatih, Istanbul, Turkey)
Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey)
Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890)
Bonfils, Felix
Türkkan, Ömer Fahrettin (Fakhri Pasha), 1868-1948
AD.MC.012
5 paige_boxes
Scope and Contents
The Engin Ozendes collection includes 315 iconic photographs taken by some of the most prominent photographers and photography studios who documented the last days of the Ottoman Empire and the early Republic period, including Abdullah Freres, Basile Kargapoulo, Zangaki, Sebah & Joaillier, Pascal Sebah, Derounian Freres, Othmar Pferschy, M. Iranian, Berggren, and Arif Hikmet Koyunoglu. The majority of the photographs, all of which are prints, date from the 1890s to 1910s.
The collection's studio photographs, from various places within the boundaries of modern-day Turkey, Syria, Iraq, Lebanon, Egypt, Greece, Palestine and Israel, present people as everything from simply children and parents, brides and grooms, to prominent military, religious and political figures. Historically significant moments related to both cultural events and military campaigns are represented as well as candid views of street life in cities and towns. The collection depicts the art and architecture from mosques and other religious and archaeological sites from throughout the region, revealing details that in some cases no longer exist, or exist in a different form today.
Arrangement
The collection was processed as it was received.
Conditions Governing Access
Digitization of this collection was completed in April 2016.
Custodial History
Akkasah, the Center for Photography at NYU Abu Dhabi, acquired the collection in December 2015.
Biographical / Historical
Engin Ozendes began researching the history of Turkish photography in 1974. Her articles on this subject have been published in numerous newspapers, magazines and encyclopedias. She has served as a jury member for many photographic competitions, and delivered lectures. In 1990 she was awarded the title Excellence Fiap (ESFIAP) by the Federation Internationale de L'Art Photographique (FIAP) for her services to photography. Between June 2004 - May 2011 she worked as Curator of Photography Exhibitions at Istanbul Museum of Modern Art. She curated many photography exhibitions internationally. Her books include Photography in the Ottoman Empire 1839-1919 (Haset Publications, 1987), Photography in the Ottoman Empire 1839-1919 (Iletisim, 1995), Abdullah Freres: Ottoman Court Photographers (Yapi Kredi. 1998), From Sebah & Joaillier to Foto Sabah: Orientalism in Photography (Yapi Kredi, 1999), Photography in Turkey (Tarih Vakfi, 1999), Merhaba Atina Here Istanbul (Tarih Vakfi, 2000), Photography in the Ottoman Empire 1839-1923 (Yapi Endustri, 2013), Modern and Contemporary Approaches to Photography in Turkey (Yapi Endustri, 2016).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection acquired from photo historian Engin Ozendes in 2015.
Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Ottoman Writing; Turkey; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Egypt; Syria
- Boy in a dark jacket, leaning on a carved wood banister. 10.6 x 6.7 cm, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Painted Backdrops; Boys; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Furnishings; Constantinople; Children; Boys; French Writing
- Man with a mustache and beard in a three-piece suit with a hat and a pin below his collar. Same man from ref3. 10.7 x 6.3 cm, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Studio Photography; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Individual Portraits; Baden, Germany; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Men; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair
- Man in a three-piece, wearing a fez and a pin below the center of his collar. 10.7 x 6.4 cm, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Baden, Germany; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Fez/Tarboush; Men; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Hats
- Seroupe Takvoryan in a three-piece suit with a striped tie. 10.4 x 6.4 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Men; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; French Writing; Individual Portraits; Neuchatel, Switzerland; Facial Hair
- Tahsin, holding sword. 10.8 x 6.8 cm, 21 Aralık 1909 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Ottoman Writing; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Swords/Knives; Individual Portraits; Weapons; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Men; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Fez/Tarboush; Facial Hair; Hats
- Mehmet Pasha. 10.4 x 6.4 cm, 29 Temmuz 1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Individual Portraits; Turkey; Pasha; Ottoman Writing; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Hats; Uniforms; Fez/Tarboush; Men; Military/Soldiers
- Woman in dress with her right hand resting on a wooden pedestal. 10.9 x 6.9 cm, June 1892 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Women; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Armenian Writing; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Therese Honegger as baby girl, sitting on a chair. Subject also in ref51 and ref69. 10.5 x 6.3 cm., 1860s; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Furnishings; Constantinople; Girls; Individual Portraits; Children; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Portrait of Sinasi Sadun on a motorcycle. 6.8 x 9.3 cm, 30 March 1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photographic Prints; Men; Individual Portraits; Ottoman Writing; Hats; Motorcycles; Turkey; Albumen Prints; Transportation; Fez/Tarboush
- Two bell ringers at the Surp Kevork Armenian church in Samatya, Istanbul. 12.2 x 8.1 cm, Undated; Victoria Portrait (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Turkish Writing; Hats; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Churches; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Religious Sites; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Second Lieutenant Nuri. Presented to Seyit Habibullah Efendi in mark of his affection. 18 x 10.8 cm, 13 October 1913 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Painted Backdrops; Weapons; Individual Portraits; Ottoman Writing; Skopje, Macedonia; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Swords/Knives; Hats; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush
- Haldun, aged 2, wearing a nautical outfit. 16.5 x 10.6 cm, 7 June 1895 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Bursa, Turkey; Ottoman Writing; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Children; Boys; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; French Writing; Greek Writing; Painted Backdrops; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Maritime/Nautical Outfits
- Haldun, aged 2, in dark outfit standing. 16.5 x 10.6 cm, 7 November 1894 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Boys; Individual Portraits; Children; Bursa, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Ottoman Writing
- Haldun in garment with belt. "To my dear Aunt Vangeli." 16.2 x 10.7 cm, 7 February 1901 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Photographic Prints; Children; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Bursa, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Carpets/Rugs; Ottoman Writing; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Studio Photography
- Haldun, in garment with belt. "To my dear grandmother and my uncles". 16.2 x 10.7 cm, 7 February 1901 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Bursa, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Carpets/Rugs; Ottoman Writing; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Children
- Woman in dress with embroidery. 16.5 x 10.5 cm, 7 January 1903 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Women; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Turkey; Individual Portraits; Ottoman Writing; Jewelry; Embroidery; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints
- Portrait of Sadun in dark jacket with belt. 16.4 x 10.4 cm, 24 December 1902 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Ottoman Writing; Children; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Boys; Hats; Turkey; Fez/Tarboush; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gloves
- Sema Sarim (?) in a print dress. 16.4 x 10.4 cm, 24 December 1902 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Ottoman Writing; Children; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople
- Portrait of Hasnun Galib in a light outfit, wearing a fez. 16.5 x 10.5 cm, 13 December 1902 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Painted Backdrops; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Children; Ottoman Writing; Furnishings; Istanbul, Turkey; Hats; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Individual Portraits; Boys
- Portrait of a soldier, holding rifle with bayonet. 18.2 x 12.5 cm, Unknown (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Furnishings; Fez/Tarboush; Guns; Men; Painted Backdrops; Individual Portraits; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Military/Soldiers; Istanbul, Turkey; Weapons; Turkish Writing; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; French Writing; Ottoman Writing; Hats
- Woman in light-colored dress. 16.6 x 10.7 cm, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Women; French Writing
- Woman with long hair standing in dark dress with buckled leather straps on her wrists. 16.2 x 10.1 cm, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Women; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Man with mustache wearing a three-piece suit and a fez. 16.2 x 10.6 cm, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Men; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Man in long coat holding a cane and hat. 16.3 x 10.4 cm, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Gloves; Men; Canes/Walking Sticks; Hats; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Individual Portraits; Constantinople; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Albumen Prints; Jewelry; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Girl in white dress with lace trim and a white bow in her hair. 16.4 x 10.8 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Individual Portraits; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Constantinople; Children; Girls; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; French Writing
- Woman in dark dress with lace trim. 16.5 x 10.7 cm, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Women; Furnishings; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; French Writing
- Man in dark coat with a flower in his lapel. 16.4 x 10.6 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Individual Portraits; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Men; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Facial Hair; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Man with mustache in suit with white bow tie and military medal on lapel. 16.5 x 10.5 cm, 11 November 1900 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Facial Hair; German Writing; Jewelry; Gloves; Books; Furnishings; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Bow Ties; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; French Writing
- A group portrait of a man and a woman with a baby wearing a lace gown. 16.6 x 10.6 cm, April 1901 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Men; Women; Children; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; English Writing; Constantinople; Furnishings; Embroidery; Bow Ties; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; French Writing
- Three brothers and their sister. Same children as ref31. 16.7 x 10.7 cm, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Boys; Girls; Children; Group Portraits; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Furnishings; Albumen Prints; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Studio Photography
- Three brothers and their sister, standing in a row. 16.4 x 10.8 cm, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Children; Boys; Girls; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Constantinople; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Albumen Prints; Group Portraits; French Writing
- Meur. & Mme Meissner Pacha and their daughter, Lucette. 16.5 x 10.5 cm, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Group Portraits; Studio Photography; Men; Women; Girls; Children; Furnishings; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Facial Hair; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Facial Hair; French Writing
- Feridun Neset as a soldier. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, 18 May 1923 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Men; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Gloves; Hats; Uniforms; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Military/Soldiers; Studio Photography; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Ottoman Writing; French Writing; Constantinople; Medals/Insignia
- Soldier standing with a downcast gaze. İhtiyat Zabit Mektebi, Harbiye, Istanbul. 13.05 x 9.1 cm, 12 April 1912 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Uniforms; Hats; Swords/Knives; Books; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Weapons; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Military/Soldiers; Men; Schools/Education; Facial Hair; Ottoman Writing; French Writing
- Group portrait with Velid Ebuzziya. 8.9 x 13.8 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Buildings; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Canes/Walking Sticks; Bow Ties; Men; Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Streets/Roads; Cameras; Facial Hair; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
- Woman in black dress with black feathers. 13.1 x 8.1 cm, 9 September 1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Turkish Writing; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Jewelry; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Women
- Portrait of Mustafa Kemal. 13.9 x 9 cm, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Hats; Painted Backdrops; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Uniforms; Men; Aleppo, Syria; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Medals/Insignia; French Writing; Atatürk, Mustafa Kemal, 1881-1938
- Three men with two shisha (hookah) pipes. 14.9 x 11.9 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Facial Hair; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Mirrors; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Facial Hair; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Men; Group Portraits; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Woman wearing hat, leaning on pillows. 16.5 x 10.5 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Furnishings; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Hats; Women; Armenian Writing
- Armenian Patriarch Nerses Varjabedyan (1837-1884), sitting, wearing Armenian clerical vestments. 16.1 x 10.7 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Men; Facial Hair; Turkish Writing; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Furnishings; Priests/Clergymen; Armenian Writing
- Two boys and one girl standing on a carpet, holding flowers. A souvenir from Mahmud Pertev Pasha. 16.7 x 10.9 cm, 18 March 1890 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carpets/Rugs; Albumen Prints; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Girls; Boys; Ottoman Writing; Children; Pasha; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Group Portraits
- Girl and a boy standing in white gowns with palm fronds at their feet. 16.5 x 10.8 cm, 1892; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Painted Backdrops; Girls; Boys; Children; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits; French Writing
- Two girls and one boy standing on a carpet with a book on a table. 16.6 x 10.8 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Boys; Girls; Books; Furnishings; Carpets/Rugs; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Children; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits; French Writing
- Kenan as a young boy in ornate dress. 16.5 x 10.8 cm, 1895; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Hats; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Carpets/Rugs; Painted Backdrops; Turkish Writing; Furnishings; Ottoman Writing; Books; Fez/Tarboush; Children; Boys; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
- Two girls, one holding a basket of flowers and the other holding a stuffed bird, and one boy sitting on a tricycle. 16.6 x 10.9 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Studio Photography; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Animals; Bicycles/Tricycles; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Painted Backdrops; Birds; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Boys; Girls; Children; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; French Writing
- Sarven and Iseda Dumentz as young girls, sitting in a rowboat. 19.8 x 15.3 cm, 20 June 1908 (Box 1, Folder Oversize)
  French Writing; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Children; Water; Boats/Ships; Painted Backdrops; Girls; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits
- Portrait of W.W. Peet, Esq. Writing, "Amerikan Bord Heyeti" stamp on back. 19.2 x 14.1 cm, 1900 (Box 1, Oversize unknown container)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Turkish Writing; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Constantinople; Facial Hair; Men; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey
- Two girls in light colored gowns sitting on furniture. 16.2 x 10.6 cm, Undated (Box 1, Oversize unknown container)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings; Children; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Painted Backdrops; Girls; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Group Portraits; Ottoman Writing; English Writing; French Writing
- Soldier with mustache in uniform and hat. 23.6 x 16.1 cm, Undated (Box 1, Oversize unknown container)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Uniforms; Facial Hair; Hats; Military/Soldiers; French Writing
- Two men in coats and hats, one man lighting his cigarette from the other's. 7.8 x 4.6 cm, Circa 1888-1910 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Facial Hair; Umbrellas/Parasols; Gloves; Canes/Walking Sticks; Constantinople; Men; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Smoking; Cigarettes; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Hats; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; French Writing
- Adele and Therese Honegger as young girls, in white gowns sitting on a chair. Therese Honegger also appears in ref8 and ref69. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, Circa 1868; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  French Writing; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Children; Girls; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; French Writing
- Arman Hisaryan as a boy standing, leaning against a table with a book in his hand. 10.6 x 6.5 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Books; Painted Backdrops; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Children; Constantinople; Boys; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; French Writing
- Man standing with walking stick. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Facial Hair; Turkish Writing; Studio Photography; Armenian Writing; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Carpets/Rugs; Canes/Walking Sticks; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Vienna, Austria; Austria; Men; Facial Hair
- Portrait of Crown Prince Mozaffar ad-Din (1853-1907), son of Naser al-Din Shah Qajar (1831-1896). 10.3 x 6.5 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; London, England, UK; Fez/Tarboush; Men; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; English Writing; Studio Photography; Hats; Facial Hair
- Portrait of Naser al-Din Shah Qajar (1831-1896) 10.3 x 6.5 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  London, England, UK; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Facial Hair; Men; Fur Garments; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; English Writing
- Portrait of Ottoman General Omer Pasha (Michael Lattas, 1801-1871). 10.5 x 6.2 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Weapons; Military/Soldiers; Medals/Insignia; Facial Hair; English Writing; Vienna, Austria; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Swords/Knives; Uniforms; Pasha; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Men; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; English Writing; Ömer Lûtfi Paşa (Omar Pasha) (Mihajlo Latas), 1806-1871
- Portrait of Muhammad III as-Sadiq (1813-1882), ruler of Tunisia from 1859-1881. Same subject as ref58. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Tunisia; Facial Hair; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Paris, France; English Writing; Men; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; French Writing
- Standing portrait of Muhammad III as-Sadiq (1813-1882), leader of Tunisia from 1859-1881. Same subject as ref57. 10.5 x 6.2 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Tunisia; Facial Hair; Paris, France; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Furnishings; Facial Hair; Men; French Writing
- Portrait of man with mustache. 10.7 x 6.6 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Facial Hair; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Izmir, Turkey; Smyrna; Albumen Prints; Men; Facial Hair; Ottoman Writing
- Man with mustache and beard sitting on a chair. 10.3 x 6.1cm, Circa 1865; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Men; Facial Hair; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Man with mustache sitting on chair, leaning on elbow on a table. 10 x 6.2 cm, Circa 1865; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 14)